[MUSIC PLAYING]
ADDY OSMANI: Do you
know what the top four
things to look at when it
comes to web accessibility are?
MATT GAUNT: Uh, no.
I can only think of two.
Like, I only think of
audio and then visual.
ADDY OSMANI: So there's
visual, hearing, mobility,
and cognition.
MATT GAUNT: Ah, OK.
So what are the last two?
ADDY OSMANI: So mobility
is where someone may not
be able to use a
mouse, or they may
need to use a keyboard to
navigate around all of your UI.
MATT GAUNT: OK, yep.
ADDY OSMANI: And
cognition is where,
if you show somebody
flashing text or a site
with lots of animation, that
might cause an epileptic fit
or just cause them issues.
MATT GAUNT: Yeah.
I think I remember
someone tweeting,
saying they had
a condition where
if there was loads of parallax
scrolling or something goes on,
it makes them feel really
nauseous, because there's tons
of weird movements going on.
ADDY OSMANI: When
doesn't parallax
scrolling make everyone feel
nauseous is the real question.
MATT GAUNT: That's true.
ADDY OSMANI: So
thankfully, there's
a few tools to help with web
accessibility issue diagnosis.
We should go through them.
The first is the Chrome
Accessibility Developer Tools,
which is like a Chrome
extension you can grab.
I'm a bit of a
douche, so I'm going
to run it against your site.
MATT GAUNT: Mine isn't too bad.
It's not great, though.
ADDY OSMANI: I guess
we'll find out.
MATT GAUNT: Yes.
ADDY OSMANI: So we're going to
hop into DevTools in the Audits
panel, check accessibility,
and go and run it
against this site.
You've got a few passing
tests, and you've
got a few tests that
are not passing.
So we're going to look at those.
The first one is yellow
and says the text
elements should have
a reasonable contrast
ratio, Matthew.
MATT GAUNT: Yeah, I set the
opacity low on some of the menu
items that aren't selected.
So I need to bump them up
or find a different way
of visualizing it.
ADDY OSMANI: One of the
nice things about this
is if you hover over
any of the DOMNodes,
it will actually
visualize it over
in the Preview pane,
which is kind of cool.
MATT GAUNT: Yeah.
So one of the other
things I found,
because I have another issue
on my site, which is the About
menu item doesn't
actually explain anything
about what's going to happen.
But if you go into the
Accessbility options,
like in the Elements
panel, and you've
got the styles and
computer styles,
there's an Accessibility
drop-down that you get.
The nice thing with
this is it actually
shows you what the
screen reader would
say based on what it's got.
And the main reason
I like this is, A,
it's a nice live representation.
It's something
that's easy for me
to go, oh, OK, this is what
the screen we would say.
But it also shows
you area labels
that you could put that would
affect the screen reader
and what it says,
which I kind of like,
because I wouldn't have
known what the right area
labels would have been.
So it's just kind of a nice
way of educating yourself
as you're going
along, figuring out
what you can change to
get better screen reader
support or anything like that.
ADDY OSMANI: Cool.
MATT GAUNT: It's nice.
ADDY OSMANI: So the
thing that powers
the accessibility
developer-produced extension
is actually called
Accessibility Developer Tools.
It's like this node module--
it's not necessarily
just a node module,
but basically, it
gives you all of the
functionality that you might
need to go and run
these tests locally
or hook up to
continuous integration
in case you wanted to
write accessibility tests
alongside your unit tests.
MATT GAUNT: Is that running
it through something
like PhantomJS?
ADDY OSMANI: So I wrote
a while back a module
called A11Y-- A-11-Y. It gives
you basically a CLI and CI
module for doing that.
And you can just go and
run it against Travis and--
MATT GAUNT: Nice.
ADDY OSMANI: --it'll
do its thing.
MATT GAUNT: Drop in your CI.
ADDY OSMANI: Drop it in.
Have you heard of Tenon?
MATT GAUNT: (WHISPERING)
Yes, I have.
ADDY OSMANI: You have?
You have.
So Tenon gives you
this nice web UI
for just doing nice, basic
web accessibility testing.
I run it against
developers.google.com,
and we have a ton of missing
alt attributes, which
we could probably fix up.
MATT GAUNT: So
Tenon is super nice.
The only criticism
I have with it--
it's great because you don't
have to do any [INAUDIBLE].
It's super easy to get a
gut check of where you are.
But the flip side is when
I ran my site through,
it says there's no
problems with it,
which we both know is now a lie.
So it's useful for a gut check.
And it's super low effort to
get it running on your site.
But I question it, I guess.
ADDY OSMANI: So Tenon runs
against the Web Content
Accessibility Guidelines 2.0.
And I think the Accessibility
Developer Tools just
has a good set of general
accessibility best practices
it tries to check against.
So they're checking for
related but not necessarily
the exact same set of things.
MATT GAUNT: Yeah.
ADDY OSMANI: They're
both worth checking out.
MATT GAUNT: So the
other one is tota11y.
ADDY OSMANI: Totally
Tooling Tips?
MATT GAUNT: No.
T-O-T-A-1-1-Y. Basically,
it's got a super awesome logo.
But what it is is it's
basically a bookmarklet.
So you can drag it
to your toolbar.
And then when you're in
your site, click on it,
and it adds a little button onto
the bottom of your web page.
And the main reason it's
nice is just the fact
that it breaks up all the
different criteria of what
you could look for in
terms of accessibility
into nice little chunks that
you just focus on that one area.
And then it starts adding
things into the page.
So with the contrast
links, it will actually
hover over the buttons, add
a little button, saying,
this is a problem area.
And it's just nice.
It's very lightweight,
it's super simple.
And I think the way
that it breaks stuff up
is if you've got a ton of
stuff wrong with your site,
it's at least manageable chunks.
So I think it's just nice.
It's a nice little tool.
ADDY OSMANI: Cool.
I've got to give a mention to
ally.js by Rodney Rehm, which
is this little helper
library that helps you
with some of the workflows
you normally have
when you're trying to make
your app a little bit more
accessible.
So it makes things like
trying to figure out
what elements are considered
focusable on the page
a little bit easier,
trapping focus
navigation to a particular
DOM subtree, something that
would have helped me, actually.
So I was trying to make
this navigation drawer
keyboard-accessible
the other day.
And I wanted to avoid you
tabbing through the navigation
and then going back--
MATT GAUNT: Yeah, getting to--
ADDY OSMANI: --and it tabbing
to the parts of the page.
So that might have
helped with that.
And it's just really useful for
querying the DOM for focusable
or tabbable elements.
Check it out.
It's pretty decent.
So I have some web
accessibility pro tips.
MATT GAUNT: Go on.
ADDY OSMANI: They're
not really pro tips.
I'm incompetent.
But they're good.
They're good things
to watch out for.
MATT GAUNT: They're
solid advice.
ADDY OSMANI: They're
So the first thing
to keep an eye on
is making sure that the
components and elements
in your page can be
accessed using a keyboard
and navigated around
using a keyboard.
Next, make sure that
your elements can
be used with a screen reader.
So for example, if I go to
your website and I turn on--
SPEAKER 1: Welcome to Voiceover.
ADDY OSMANI: --voiceover--
SPEAKER 1: Voiceover
speaks descriptions
of items on the screen.
ADDY OSMANI: It's
basically what it does.
SPEAKER 2: Voiceover
on Chromium.
Unit testing a service worker.
[INAUDIBLE] vertical line
Matt Gaunt.
ADDY OSMANI: So it
does all of that.
MATT GAUNT: The
vertical line one
is the interesting one where
I've somehow added my name
to the single vertical line.
So there's some issues there.
ADDY OSMANI: We've already
discovered in this episode
that you have multiple
issues with your site
probably worth checking out.
MATT GAUNT: [LAUGHS]
ADDY OSMANI: People
should also make sure
that their apps
work without sound.
So things like games might be
worth keeping that in mind.
MATT GAUNT: Something like Air
Horn, though, where all it is
is a button that makes a horn.
ADDY OSMANI: You could probably
make that accessible, like
show a bubble or something.
MATT GAUNT: Because
I didn't know.
It was just a text that
just goes, whooo-on.
ADDY OSMANI: [LAUGHS]
People should
make sure their apps
work without color,
because some people are
colorblind and don't see
the full spectrum of colors.
MATT GAUNT: Yup.
ADDY OSMANI: And
people should make sure
that their web apps work in
high-contrast mode as well.
MATT GAUNT: Which is the problem
that I've got on my site.
ADDY OSMANI: You have
multiple problems, Matt.
These are just some of the
ones that we can actually
address using tools.
MATT GAUNT: Thanks, man.
ADDY OSMANI: I try.
I try.
[MUSIC PLAYING]